<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Retro Games on The GameLog Archive</title><link>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/categories/retro-games/</link><description>Recent content in Retro Games on The GameLog Archive</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/categories/retro-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Risky Woods (邪神ドラクソス)</title><link>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/genesis/risky-woods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/genesis/risky-woods/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risky-woods---sega-genesis-邪神ドラクソス">Risky Woods - SEGA GENESIS (邪神ドラクソス)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Risky Woods (Jashin Draxos) is a side-scrolling action game released by EA for the Sega Mega Drive in December 1992 in North America and Europe, and in February 1993 in Japan by EA Victor. The game features a solid system that combines time-limited stages, rescuing petrified monks, weapon upgrades, armor enhancements, and puzzle-solving elements.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-basic-overview-and-release-information">1. Basic Overview and Release Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Risky Woods&lt;/strong> is a fantasy-themed side‑scrolling action platformer originally developed by Spain’s Dinamic Software and Zeus Software for the Amiga and released in 1992. It was later ported by Electronic Arts (EA) to the Sega Mega Drive and published in North America and Europe in December 1992, and in Japan under the title &lt;strong>邪神ドラクソス&lt;/strong> (Jashin Draxos, &lt;em>Death God Draxos&lt;/em>) on February 19, 1993. EA handled distribution in North America and Europe, while the Japanese version was released by EA Victor. The game also saw local releases in Brazil (Tec Toy) and South Korea (Samsung Electronics), where it became known by the phonetic rendering of its Japanese name, &lt;strong>사신 드락소스&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shin Nekketsu Kōha: Kunio‑tachi no Banka</title><link>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/snes/shin-nekketsu-k%C5%8Dha-kuniotachi-no-banka-2player-coop/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 14:04:21 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/snes/shin-nekketsu-k%C5%8Dha-kuniotachi-no-banka-2player-coop/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="shin-nekketsu-kōha-kuniotachi-no-banka---sfc-新熱血硬派くにおたちの挽歌">Shin Nekketsu Kōha: Kunio‑tachi no Banka - SFC (新・熱血硬派くにおたちの挽歌)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>On April 29, 1994, Shin Nekketsu Kōha: Kunio‑tachi no Banka—developed by Almanic Corporation under the Technōs Japan brand and published by Technōs Japan—was released exclusively for the Super Famicom as a belt‑scroll action game. It is distinguished by its departure from the series’ comedic presentation, instead adopting realistic character proportions and dramatic dialogue sequences.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-basic-overview-and-release-information">1. Basic Overview and Release Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Title&lt;/strong>: Shin Nekketsu Kōha: Kunio‑tachi no Banka&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Platform&lt;/strong>: Super Famicom (SFC)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Genre&lt;/strong>: Belt‑Scroll Action (Beat ’em up)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Release Date&lt;/strong>: April 29, 1994 (Japan)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Developer&lt;/strong>: Almanic Corporation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Publisher&lt;/strong>: Technōs Japan&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="2-development-and-production-background">2. Development and Production Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This entry was directed by series creator Yoshihisa Kishimoto, with producer Noriyuki Tomiyama, sound programmer Michiya Hirasa, composer Kazunaka Yamane, and scenario writer Hiro Yokokura as core staff.&lt;br>
By outsourcing development to Almanic instead of in‑house Technōs Japan, the game’s engine and level design concepts later influenced Super Mad Champ. An early PlayStation sequel was planned but never released.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>