<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Platformer on The GameLog Archive</title><link>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/tags/platformer/</link><description>Recent content in Platformer on The GameLog Archive</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/tags/platformer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Risky Woods (邪神ドラクソス)</title><link>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/genesis/risky-woods/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/genesis/risky-woods/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="risky-woods---sega-genesis-邪神ドラクソス">Risky Woods - SEGA GENESIS (邪神ドラクソス)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Risky Woods (Jashin Draxos) is a side-scrolling action game released by EA for the Sega Mega Drive in December 1992 in North America and Europe, and in February 1993 in Japan by EA Victor. The game features a solid system that combines time-limited stages, rescuing petrified monks, weapon upgrades, armor enhancements, and puzzle-solving elements.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-basic-overview-and-release-information">1. Basic Overview and Release Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Risky Woods&lt;/strong> is a fantasy-themed side‑scrolling action platformer originally developed by Spain’s Dinamic Software and Zeus Software for the Amiga and released in 1992. It was later ported by Electronic Arts (EA) to the Sega Mega Drive and published in North America and Europe in December 1992, and in Japan under the title &lt;strong>邪神ドラクソス&lt;/strong> (Jashin Draxos, &lt;em>Death God Draxos&lt;/em>) on February 19, 1993. EA handled distribution in North America and Europe, while the Japanese version was released by EA Victor. The game also saw local releases in Brazil (Tec Toy) and South Korea (Samsung Electronics), where it became known by the phonetic rendering of its Japanese name, &lt;strong>사신 드락소스&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Batman: The Video Game (NES)</title><link>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/nes/batman-the-video-game-nes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:19:21 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://retrogamelog.github.io/en/walkthrough/nes/batman-the-video-game-nes/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="batman-the-video-game---nes">Batman: The Video Game - NES&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>This post covers the overall details of the NES Batman game developed by Sunsoft (known as “Batman: The Video Game” in North America and 「バットマン」 in Japan), including its detailed level structure, walkthrough, basic overview and release information, development background, game system, and reviews.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h2 id="1-basic-overview-and-release-information">1. Basic Overview and Release Information&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Title and Regional Differences&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>North American Version:&lt;/strong> “Batman: The Video Game”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Japanese Version:&lt;/strong> 「バットマン」&lt;br>
Depending on the region, the cover design, title font, and release dates vary slightly. The game was first released in Japan on December 22, 1989, and in North America in 1990. The European version was unveiled in the latter part of 1990.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Development and Publishing&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>